<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Jozef Sukovsky</title>
    <link>https://sukovsky.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Jozef Sukovsky</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Jozef Sukovsky</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 19:20:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sukovsky.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Stress-testing Django, Django REST framework, FastAPI, Express.js, Go-chi and Axum</title>
      <link>https://sukovsky.com/posts/5-stress-testing-django-drf-fastapi-expressjs-go-chi-axum/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 19:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sukovsky.com/posts/5-stress-testing-django-drf-fastapi-expressjs-go-chi-axum/</guid>
      <description>Intro While working with different stack combinations, I sometimes wonder about the true throughput/performance of each solution. It is not straightforward to compare them because every product is unique and possesses different features and design choices. However, some things can still be compared, even though not everything will be a fair comparison. This will be comparing apples with pears, plums and other fruits to get an idea of the capacity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Django user trying out FastAPI</title>
      <link>https://sukovsky.com/posts/4-django-user-trying-out-fastapi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 20:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sukovsky.com/posts/4-django-user-trying-out-fastapi/</guid>
      <description>Django was my first choice for many years. But building new API-driven products using Django and Django REST Framework never brought that pleasing feeling I would like to feel.&#xA;The Good, the Bad and the Ugly It&amp;rsquo;s been around 2007 I stumbled upon Django framework. Needed to build a very simple image gallery, nothing serious. And since then, every time I had to do something to be displayed on the web, Django was my first choice.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Technical debt will eat your feet</title>
      <link>https://sukovsky.com/posts/3-tech-debt-will-eat-feet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sukovsky.com/posts/3-tech-debt-will-eat-feet/</guid>
      <description>No matter what you believe, no matter what you do. If you befriended Technical Debt, you already know, what&amp;rsquo;s coming. Eventually.&#xA;Here and there, social networks offer some technical debt related brawls, jokes, memes and more or less relevant thoughts. My thoughts are the grumpy ones.&#xA;The boring part The boring part of technical debt is it&amp;rsquo;s formal nature. Which is very well described in here Technical Debt. I won&amp;rsquo;t be re-inventing wheel talking about theory.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Python Imports</title>
      <link>https://sukovsky.com/posts/2-about-python-imports/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sukovsky.com/posts/2-about-python-imports/</guid>
      <description>Seeing some code snippets, sometimes hurts. Sometimes it hurts even more, realizing I&amp;rsquo;m the author. But very often, it hurts right in the beginning of the file. The imports.&#xA;How this should be according to the theory Every other code editor or IDE has at least some possibility of linting. That&amp;rsquo;s the feature which will bother you to fix some stuff while writing your code. Even though, many people just consider it some game, where sustaining these suggestions is the goal of it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyberton theme</title>
      <link>https://sukovsky.com/posts/1-hugo-cyberton-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 02:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sukovsky.com/posts/1-hugo-cyberton-theme/</guid>
      <description>Before I launched my website, I decided to make my life harder by creating an open-source Hugo theme. And the earth would stop rolling, if I hadn&amp;rsquo;t written this post about it.&#xA;TL;DR This site uses Hugo. It is a static site generator written in Hugo. No dependency hell called node_modules. Many themes of various qualities can be found here. I was curious, how horrible it will be making my own.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
